# Ilona Krieva

Manchester - ilonakrieva@gmail.com - 07967649695

#### **PROFILE**

Customer Service with Excellent Service Delivery. Decade Experience of Diverse Cultural Backgrounds. Administrating tasks while Liaising with Other Teams to Enhance Best Experience. Core competencies include Customer Service, Clerical Administration, Cultural Differences, Event Coordinator, and Hospitality.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Coop Legal Services (Manchester, UK)

Customer Service Probate Advisor, September 2022 – Present

- Providing Legal guidance and Support to Clients with High Level of Accuracy. Delivering high Standard Customer Service via Phone, Email or Writing and Distinguishing the Approach for each Customer Individually. Gathering Information from Client to Identify best Solution for their Individual Needs while maintain High level of Confidentiality.
- Completing a Variety of ad-hoc Tasks and Support the Team. Strictly following Guidelines while being Flexible with Customers. Accurately inputting Information into System.

#### Coop Funeralcare (Manchester, UK)

**Upskilled CBS Advisor**, February 2021 – September 2022

- Delivering high Standard Customer Service by Providing Info, Advice and Guidance by Distinguishing the Approach for each customer Individually. Engaging with Customers by Using Empathy skills and Emotional Intelligence for Bereaved clients and putting Customers Mind at Ease.
- Supporting Customer Journey through Administrative tasks Using Different Systems and mail Inboxes while Liaising with Different Teams from various Departments. Monitoring efficiency of the process.
- Handling 8 different Call Lines due to be Equipped with new Trainings. Attention to Details to Create new Cases in Busy Environment. Sustaining great relationships with other departments for efficient results.

#### University of Manchester (Manchester, UK)

Barista Supervisor, January 2018 – November 2020

- Ensuring high Standards and Excellent Customer Service were Consistently met by Providing Customers with prompt Service, Quality beverages and food in a friendly, Fast-paced Environment.
- Increasing Efficiency by re-arranging the work Environment and Developing Time-saving Measures to deal with Large Number of customers. Introduced Seasonal themes.
- Planning Purchases ahead Meticulously to Maximize ROI. Monitoring Purchases and Invoices via Phone and Emails. This new Approach has been used by the Management as an Example for other Units.

# Latvian Student Fellowship Organization - LKSB (Riga, Latvia) International Student Officer, November 2004 – February 2011

• Planning and Organising Events and Conferences to Welcome and Celebrate International Students. Organising Events for Education Purposes about Cultural Differences and Hospitality possibilities for International Students and Locals to build Connections.

- Conducting Collaborations with Local Universities and Charities to Create Welcome Strategy events for International students in Latvia. Coordinating group of Volunteers to Conduct and Execute Events and Activities.
- Administration: Preparing learning Materials, Keping Records, Monitoring and Following through Progress and Lists while using Several Mailboxes. Creating Newsletters for Supporters, Updated Social Media, Arranging Logistics and Successfully Coordinating meetings and Information between all Involved Parties.

#### A/S Kvadra Pak, Printing House (Riga, Latvia)

Logistic Department Assistant, May 2002 – August 2003

• Communicating with Customers via Phone or Email for Product and Invoice Preparations. Collaborating with Storage Managers on a Regular Basis to Monitor and Coordinate Documents with the actual Content. Preparing Export Freights for Shipments. Coordinating the Transport Flow, writing Reports to ensure Accurate Information Circulation.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Youth Homeless Charity, Depaul UK (Manchester, UK)

Mentor May 2022 – present)

• Mentoring Young People to be / do Better in Life through One-to-One meetings and occasional Cooking Sessions in Safehouse centre.

City Church Manchester (Manchester, UK)

Hospitality Service Leader, June 2016 – August 2017

- Establishing and Expanding multiple Teams of Volunteers to Serve Beverages and Snacks.
- Coordinating group of Volunteers. Preparing and Delivering Training for Volunteers to remain Consistent.

University of Salford (Salford, UK)

Radical Youth President, November 2014 – November 2015

• Leading by Example the Team of Volunteers, Planning and Organising Events with Team and Providing Support and Growth to the Team.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Salford** 

THEATRE AND PERFORMANCE PRACTICE (BA), 2.1, September 2014 – July 2017

*Program Highlights:* Theatre Making, Perform Approaches Workshop, Acting for Camera, Presenting, Performance Skills, Performance in Context, New trends in Theatre, Critical & Textual Studies

West Lancashire College Skelmersdale Campus

PERFORMING ARTS (BTEC LEVEL 3), DDD, September 2012 – July 2014

#### **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

Microsoft Office, Sales Force, Outlook, CallGuard, Genesis, HEAT, CRM, Guardian, Proclaim

#### LANGUAGES

English (Fluent) – Latvian (Native) - Russian (Fluent)

## **HOLDER OF DRIVING LICENSE**